David Padilla

Full Stack Web Developer

Portfolio davidpadilla.io GitHub github.com/dpadillajs

Experience in crafting clean, modern web designs with server-based operations using both relational and non-relational databases. Over 16 handson GitHub projects demonstrating proficiency in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Node.js, and others.

Successful in working both team and self-directed settings to meet coding project deadlines. Proven ability to quickly master new technologies.

Personal Info

Phone

+1 919 869 9647

Email

davidpadilla.dev@gmail.com

Address

Raleigh, NC 27615

Technical Skills

FRONT END TECHNOLOGIES

HTML5

CSS3

Bootstrap 4

Material-UI

JavaScript

ES6

jQuery

Handlebars

Firebase

React

BACK END TECHNOLOGIES

Node.js

Express

NoSQL

MongoDB

Mongoose

MySQL

Sequelize

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES

RESTful APIs

MVC Architecture

JSON

AJAX

Debugging Tools

Project Experience

2019-04

Recipedia

Full Stack Web Developer

Recipedia is a MERN-stack application that makes weekly meal planning easier. Designed with the busy professional in mind, the site allows users to search for recipes, favorite them for future reference, and build a weekly menu.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Created authentication with **Firebase** so that users can signup as a registered member or demo the application with limited features as an anonymous guest.
- Formulated API calls within a NodeJS development environment using MongoDB queries to allow the user to search for recipes with filtering options.
- Designed multiple webpages using Material-UI as a component library for React.

https://mv-recipedia.com/

2019-03

Personal Portfolio

Front-end Web Developer

My personal portfolio is the culmination of some of my best work that's stylized in a sleek modern web design made from scratch. Mobile responsiveness across all devices with optimization for viewport widths as small as 320px.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Integrated multiple jQuery plugins with HTML and CSS alterations to match the visual identity of the website.
- Investigated bugs using DevTools to deliver synchronous code solutions caused by the limitations of **jQuery**'s rendering speed.
- Utilized **Bootstrap** and media queries to deliver responsiveness to mobile devices.

https://www.davidpadilla.io/

2019-02

Gamelogger

Full Stack Web Developer

Gamelogger is a full stack application that allows gamers to keep track of their videogames in progress. Gamers can then go back to mark them as completed once they're finished saving the world.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Constructed a data model for MySQL operations to exist for managing videogames.
- Simplified complex database queries using Sequelize as an object-relational mapper from open source software (**NPM**).
- Improved readability of code by following an MVC Architecture for folder structuring and using **Handlebars** for semantic templating.

https://gamelogger-app.herokuapp.com/



Education

2018-10 -

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Coding Boot Camp - Full Stack Web Development Certification

2019-04

An intensive 24 week program dedicated to building full stack web applications.